对于对手球队的支持者来说，你已经成为了自己的恶棍。
To opponents' team supporters, you have become your own kind of villain.
我只看自己，不看别人。
I just look at myself, I never look at the others.
我不在乎球迷说什么、对手或主教练说什么。
I don't care what the fans say or the opponents or the managers.
我只是帮助我的后卫四人组，并尽力做出尽可能多的扑救。
I just help my back four and I try to make as many saves as I can.
今天我的客人是一位精英守门员，他是智力游戏中的马格努斯·卡尔森。
My guest today is an elite goalkeeper who's the Magnus Carlsen of mind games.
六英尺五英寸的臀部晃动人群嘘罚球击退威胁
six foot five inches of hip shaking crowd shushing penalty repelling menace
就在本周，他三年来第二次被评为国际足联最佳男子门将。
Just this week, he was named FIFA's best men's goalkeeper for the second time in three years.
就在两年前的今天，他相当热情地
And exactly two years ago to this day, he rather enthusiastically
随阿根廷队夺得世界杯冠军后，他接受了金手套奖杯。
accepted the gold glove trophy after winning the World Cup with Argentina.
非常高兴欢迎阿斯顿维拉的埃米·马丁内斯先生。
It's an incredible joy to welcome Aston Villa's Mr. Emi Martinez.
你好，罗格。
Hello, Rog.
你还好吗，伙计？
You all right, mate?
哦，我现在是，艾美，因为我们在你发表讲话几天后...
Oh, I am now, Emmy, because we are speaking just a few days after you made...
对于一些门将来说，在对阵诺丁汉森林队的比赛中，什么是决定职业生涯的扑救？
What for some goalkeepers would be a career-defining save against Nottingham Forest?
不知怎的，尼古拉斯·多明格斯的近距离头球被挡出。
Somehow denied a header from Nicolas Dominguez at point-blank range.
这就像在背后进行扑救并增加了旋转。
It's like a behind the back save with added spin.
这是锅守门员脚。
It's pot goalkeeping feet.
就像《碟中谍》的特技一样。
Like, part Mission Impossible stunt.
你看到了什么...
What did you see...
您是如何经历的以及那一刻的感觉如何？
How did you experience it and how did it feel in that moment?
好吧，公平地说，我只是想获得一些空间
Well, to be fair, I was trying to get some space
为了接住十字架，你知道，我总是，你知道，我会保持前页脚来尝试做高要求。
to catch the cross, you know, I'm always, you know, I go keep a front footer to try and do the high claims.
然后我就
And then I was
我前面有很多人，你知道，而且球真的很好地进入了近门柱，他们无法来。
a lot of bodies in front of me, you know, and the ball was really good into the near post, they couldn't come.
我认为他们，吉普斯威，他轻弹了它，然后多明格斯就从那里得到了它
And I think they, Gipsway, he flicked it and then Dominguez just had it from
我不知道，两码，你知道，我的头球很好，实际上是冲向球门的，然后我看到球在我身后。
I don't know, two yards, you know, and I was a good header actually towards the goal and then I saw the ball behind me.
不知何故，我们只是试图将其拖回游戏中以产生一点力量，然后
And somehow we just try to drag it back into play to generate a little bit of power and then
我没碰它。
I didn't touch it.
你知道，通常球会通过你的双手，或者如果你试图把球带回来，你就会打进乌龙球。
You know, normally it goes through your hands or you score an own goal if you try to bring it back.
所以我必须旋转球的另一侧以确保我不会碰到它。
So I have to spin the other side of the ball to make sure I don't touch it.
但最后我们输掉了比赛，所以有点沮丧。
But we lost the game at the end, so a little bit frustrated.
旋转。
The spin.
将其逆转至球门线。
to reverse it for the goal line.
所有这些想法都在那一瞬间发生。
All that thinking in like that second.
旋转只是本能吗，Em？
Is the spin just instinct, Em?
我选择我的手跟随，你知道，
I choose my hand followed, you know,
当我旋转背部时，我的手、我的身体也跟着旋转。
When I spun my back, my hand, my body followed.
所以这不是我现在的想法，只是，你知道，
So it's not something I thought at the moment, it's just, you know,
有了这样的扑救，你就必须横扫。
With that kind of save, you have to sweep.
这就是你训练的东西。
And that's something you train.
杰米雷德克纳普在英国电视上表示，他认为这是英超联赛中最伟大的扑救。
Jamie Redknapp on English TV said he thought it was the greatest save of the Premier League.
时代对你来说不是时代的赛季，它甚至能进入你的前五名吗？从技术上来说，你把它排在哪里
era not the season of the era for you does it even crack your top five where do you rank this technically
对我来说，我并没有真正将自己排在其他人之中，但对我来说，
For me, I don't really rank myself amongst the others, but for me it was,
这是我最好的一次扑救，也是我技术最好的守门扑救。
It was my best one, my best technical skill goalkeeping save.
所以，你知道，而且
So, you know, and
这是我应该感到自豪的事情，因为即使在这个年纪我仍然在不断进步。
and that's something I should be proud of because even at this age I keep improving.
这是令人惊奇的，守门员的旅程。
which is amazing, the goalkeeper's journey.
我知道你曾与心理学家大卫·普里斯特利（David Priestley）合作来建立这种心态。
And I know you've worked with a psychologist, David Priestley, to build that mindset.
在阿森纳，你和他的会面提到了对你周末表现的投资
at Arsenal you've called your meetings with him quote an investment into your weekend performances
您能向我们描述一下您在游戏中关键时刻保持积极情绪的心理过程吗？
Can you describe to us the mental process you go through in game to maintain positivity in key moments?
是的，他也是我成功的关键之一，你知道，让我留在那里。
Yeah, he's one of the major keys for my success as well, you know, to keep me there.
你知道，永远不会太低，也永远不会太高，你知道，让我保持平衡，你知道，让我保持一致。
you know, never too low and never too high, you know, keep me balanced, you know, keep me consistent.
这就是为什么对于职业运动员来说，保持这种一致性是一件更困难的事情
and that's why for professional athletes it's a harder thing to do to maintain that consistency
你知道，在职业生涯的六年、七年或十年内，一个赛季打了 60 场比赛。
for 60 games in a season over six, seven years or 10 years of career, you know.
这让我在职业生涯的最后六年或七年里
And that's something that made me for my last six years of my career or seven has been
超级稳定，每个赛季都在进步，这就是我想要的结局。
super consistent, improving every season and that's how I want to finish.
众所周知，你的小腿上有一个世界杯奖杯的纹身。
You famously have a tattoo on your calf of the World Cup trophy.
两年前你就赢了。
You won it two years ago.
你把它画在你腿上你救球的确切位置。
And you had it inked in the exact spot on your leg where you saved that shot.
弗朗西斯·兰德尔·科纳·莫阿纳 (Francis Randall Kona Moana) 为您在决赛中赢得了加时。
From Francis Randall Kona Moana, you get extra time at the final.
阿根廷自1986年以来首次夺得世界杯冠军。
Argentina's first World Cup win since 1986.
日常生活中，当你俯视自己的腿时，你会经历什么情绪？
What emotions do you experience on the daily when you look down on your leg?
当你看到那个奖杯回头看你时，你就会想到自己在赢得它的过程中发挥的关键作用。
you see that trophy looking back at you and you think about your own key part in winning it.
是的，这太神奇了，因为我们...
Yeah, it's amazing because we...
在我们输掉第一场比赛后，我们和我在国家队的一些队友打了赌。
We made a bet with some of my mates in the national teams after we lost the first game.
我说，如果我们赢得世界杯，我们也会纹上我们的名字和球衣号码。
I say, if we win the World Cup, we're going to do a tattoo with our names as well, with our shirt numbers.
所以当我救出那个球并且我们赢得了世界杯时，他们都说，我们都知道你要在哪里纹身。
So when I saved that ball and we won the World Cup, they all said, we all know where you're going to do the tattoo.
你必须在那里做，你必须在那个地方做。
You have to do it there, you have to do it in that spot.
我只是将星星放在球击中的确切位置。
I just put the star in the exact spot where the ball hit.
所以当它出现在我的纹身中时，22 颗星正是球击中的位置。
So when it's in my tattoo, the 22 star is exactly where the ball hit.
当你看到它时，你有什么感觉？
And when you look at it, what do you feel?
只是骄傲。
Just proud.
你知道，我很小的时候就来到了英国，你知道，不会说英语。
You know, I came to England with such a young age, you know, without speaking the language.
不同的天气，不同的人，不同的文化。
different weather, different people and different culture.
回望16年前，
Looking back 16 years ago,
我仍然很自豪能够来到这里，成为奖项冠军，赢得如此多的头衔和个人奖项。
I'm still proud to be here, being an award champion, winning so many titles and individual awards.
这让我感到自豪。
It just makes me proud.
它让我继续前进。
It makes me keep going.
我总是回顾过去，帮助我不断进步。
I always look back to help me to keep improving.
有点乱。
Little messy.
罗萨里奥出生，现居迈阿密，是人类奇迹。
Rosario born, now Miami-based, human wonder.
他称你为世界上最好的守门员。
He's called you the best goalkeeper in the world.
自 2017 年起你就和他一起在阿根廷国家队踢球。
And you played with him on the Argentinian national team since 2017.
我并不是说这是一个奇怪的问题。
And I don't mean this as a weird question.
但作为新人，加入国家队的时候，见到他会紧张吗？
But as new players, when you join the national team, are you nervous when you meet him?
因为对于世界来说，梅西就是神。
Because to the world, Messi is a god.
但过了一段时间，他会变得像一个正常的队友一样，还是留在更衣室里，留在球场上？
But after a while, does he just become like a normal teammate or does he remain in the locker room, on the field?
玩山羊气场的绅士？
a gent who plays with goat aura?
不，公平地说，
No, to be fair,
对于所有球员来说，也许是的，但对我来说，你知道，
With all the players, maybe yes, but for me, you know,
我们都一样，你知道，我是一个非常好斗的小伙子。
We all the same, you know, I'm very, you know, a fighting lad.
我给大家开玩笑。
I make jokes to everyone.
他身上有一种谁都没有的气场。
he's got an aura that no one has.
你知道，他是这样的人，
You know, he's someone like,
你尊敬他，当你看到他时，无论他做什么，你都会尝试模仿。
you look up to, when you see him, whatever he does, you try to copy.
他去健身房，你去健身房，他就有那种气场。
He goes to the gym, you go to the gym, he's got that aura.
我认为足球界没有人拥有这一点。
that I think no one in football have.
但后来
But then
对我来说，每个人都是一样的。
For me, everyone is the same.
我们都开玩笑，你知道，我们一起吃饭。
We all joke, you know, we have meals together.
他是一个可爱的人，但他拥有超级天赋。
He's a lovely human being, but he has a super talent.
当你生来就拥有无人拥有的超级天赋时，他就是那个人。
When you're born with a super talent that no one has, he's that man.
就像约翰·麦金或者……
It's like John McGinn or...
是的，就像几内亚一样，是的。
Yeah, like guinea, yeah.
在那届世界杯决赛中，您谈到了如何向阿根廷队友介绍如何罚点球。
In that World Cup final, you've talked about how you briefed your Argentinian teammates how to take their penalties.
击败你的法国对手雨果·洛里斯。
to beat your French opponent, Hugo Lloris.
你很难得分。
You are incredibly difficult to score against.
你是出了名的难搞。
You're famously difficult.
你说过，在那些时刻，我拥有我的盒子。
And you've said, quote, in those moments, I own my box.
你能解释一下是什么让你在点球大战中如此具有统治力吗？
Can you break down what makes you so bloody dominant in penalties, any kind of penalty?
但这是准备吗？
But is it preparation?
智力是了解对手的倾向还是只是本能
intelligence is it learning your opponent's tendencies or is it just instinct
我认为比赛中的点球只是点球。
I think a penalty during the game is just a penalty.
点球大战是一项不同的运动，我很擅长，你知道，我就是这么看的，你知道
a penalty shootout is a different sport and I'm pretty good at it you know that's how I see it you know
而这艘船，我是最好的。
And this boat, I'm the best.
我从来不认为我是最好的...
I never think I'm the best in...
在进球，正常的进球，但在那一刻，我想我击败了另一个守门员。
in goal, normal goal, but in that moment, I think I beat the other goalkeeper.
你知道，因为有五个射手。
you know, because it's five shooters.
我认为
I think
拯救两个，再加上三个，你就赢得了平局。
saving two, plus maybe three, you win the tie.
你知道，我总是支持自己说一两句话。
And I always back myself to say one or two, you know.
我就是这样经历的。
And that's how I go through it.
即使你进了第一个，我仍然会救两个。
Even if you score the first one, I'm still going to save two.
如果你进了第二个，我仍然会救两个。
If you score the second one, I'm still going to save two.
所以我心理上...
So I'm mentally...
在那些时刻真的很坚强。
really strong in those moments.
对于守门员来说，这可能是他们唯一感受到一点压力的时刻。
For goalkeepers, that's the only moment maybe they got a little bit of pressure.
因为如果他们不救前两个并且他们都继续追随我们，那么他们的精神就会下降。
because if they don't save the first two and they all keep at us, mentally they drop.
所以这就是为什么我真的强迫自己在前三场比赛中扑出一个球，只是为了给另一名门将施加压力。
So that's why I really pushed myself to save one in the first three, just to push the pressure on the other goalkeeper.
我的意思是，这是一项不同的运动，如果点球大战是一项奥林匹克运动，你可能会获得奥运金牌。
I mean, it is a different sport, and you would probably Olympic gold if Penalty Shootout was an Olympic sport.
但我钦佩你的一点是，Emi，你几乎把迷惑其他玩家变成了一种艺术形式。
But what I admire about you, Emi, is that you've turned psyching out other players almost into an art form.
是否要求官员检查金斯利科曼是否将球放在正确的位置。
Whether it's asking officials to check Kingsley Coman had put the ball on the right spot.
问曼联队的布鲁诺·费尔南德斯为什么他当时的队友克里斯蒂亚诺没有主罚点球。
Asking Manchester United's Bruno Fernandes why his then-teammate Cristiano wasn't taking the penalty.
甚至在欧联杯点球大战前嘘里尔球迷。
or even shushing Lille supporters before a shootout in the Europa Conference League.
我的意思是，你提前计划好这种***装饰吗？
I mean, do you plan this kind of ***thousery in advance?
或者它只是发生在当下？
Or does it just happen in the moment?
对球员、球迷、比赛、当下的反应？
A reaction to the players, to the fans, to the match, to the moment?
不，就目前而言，你知道，我从来没有计划过任何事情。
No, just at the moment, you know, I never plan anything.
你知道，当我说第一句话时
You know, when I say the first
然后我尝试给球员们制造一点压力。
Then I tried to create a little bit of pressure on the players.
但仅此而已。
But no more than that.
人们做了更糟糕的事情，但他们却侥幸逃脱了惩罚。
people who do worse things and they get away with it.
但我错过了主场联赛的半决赛，因为
But I miss a Conference League semi-final at home because
裁判因为我要球而给了我一张黄牌。
the ref gave me a yellow for asking for a ball.
所以现在我得到了这样的声誉
So now I got a reputation that
你知道会让人们生气，但那不是那是不正确的
that you know wind people up and that's not that's not correct
两个对手，一个球队的支持者。
Two opponents, team supporters.
你已经成为你自己的恶棍了。
You have become your own kind of villain.
你肯定会倾向于这一点，艾米。
You definitely do lean into that, Emi.
打倒对手，打倒对方球迷……
Winding up opponents, winding up opposing fans...
有时确实感觉这有时会与焦点发生冲突。
It does feel sometimes that that can clash with the focus sometimes.
区域，你需要排斥的浓度
the zone, the concentration that you need to repel
所有来者。
all comers.
您自己认为如何平衡两者？
How would you balance the two in your own mind?
或者你会从别人的弱点中汲取力量吗？
Or do you draw strength from others' weaknesses?
我只看自己，不看别人。
I just look at myself, I never look at the others.
当我上场或参加点球大战时，我会去赢得比赛。
When I go onto the pitch or on a penalty shootout, I go and win it.
这就是我所关心的。
That's all I care.
我不在乎球迷说什么、对手或主教练说什么。
I don't care what the fans say or the opponents or the managers.
我只是帮助我的后卫四人组，并尽力做出尽可能多的扑救。
I just help my back four and I try to make as many saves as I can.
最后一个问题要问你，埃米·马丁内斯。
Last question for you, Emi Martinez.
这个赛季，我们询问所有与我们交谈过的球员，
This season, we're asking all of the players that we speak to,
如果你的余生只能听一首歌，你会选择什么？为什么？
If you could only listen to one song for the rest of your life, what would it be and why?
Tres estrelas en el conjunto，这是我们赢得世界杯后的阿根廷歌曲。
Tres estrellas en el conjunto, which is the Argentinian song after we win the World Cup.
谢谢你，伙计。
Thank you, mate.
大爱，大爱。
Big, big love.
谢谢，重。
Thanks, heavy.
谢谢，菲利普。
Thanks, Philip.
勇气。
Courage.